Setumadhava Giridhar Kathawate

Product Design Generalist With A Passion For Solving People Problems Through Human Centered Design.

206-739-4983 setugk8@gmail.com Seattle, WA <u>www.setumadhava.com</u>

About

Product designer having 3 years of experience in designing products, seeking opportunities to solve complex user & business problems through elegant, research-informed product & experience designs. Other interests include Machine Learning, Behavioral Psychology & Cooking.

Skills

Primary UX Skills: Interaction Design, Prototyping, Visual design, Framer, Invision, Sketch, Product Strategy, Project Scoping, Cross-functional Collaboration, Agile Development Process, Remote & Inperson User Research Methods, Usable Product Design, HTML/CSS.

Meta Skills: Awareness, Responsibility & Ownership, Integrity, Decision making, Resourceful, Critical thinking, Problem solving, Constant learning, Passion for reading books.

Experience

UX DESIGNER, UW MEDICINE

DEC 2017 - PRESENT

- Designed web & mobile experiences as a part of UW Medicine's website redesign efforts.
- Key Accomplishment: Owned the responsibility & delivered 14 high-fidelity, production-ready
 mockups of web & mobile screens in 2 days, after the contracted design agency failed to deliver the
 screen designs on-time, ensuring there was no delay in the project timelines.

CO-FOUNDER & PRODUCT DESIGNER, EVENTOSAUR

MAR 2015 - PRESENT

- Leading a distributed team of designers & non-designers to build a SaaS product to solve the problem of order, inventory & team management for event vendors in India.
- Key Accomplishment: Co-founded a profitable event-planning start-up & worked remotely while in grad school to design a web-app that solved the problem of vendor discovery & reduced the complexity in traditional event planning for millennials in India.

UX DESIGNER, PREMERA BLUE CROSS

MAY 2017 - DEC 2017

- Led the UX efforts to design a Provider Search tool to help Premera's customers confidently find the providers or facilities covered by their insurance plan.
- **Key Accomplishment**: Average customer satisfaction score went up from 2.8 to 4.1 (on a scale of 1-5) after shipping the new search experience.

INTERACTION DESIGN INTERN, EXPEDIA INC

JUN 2016 - SEP 2016

- Conceptualized & designed a mobile web interface to explore alternative hotel shopping experience for Expedia's customers by simplifying the beds & occupancy preferences, room browsing & checkout process.
- Key Learnings: Collaboration in a large UX Organization, designing for accessibility, cross-functional collaboration, project & time management.

Education

MASTER'S IN HUMAN CENTERED DESIGN & ENGINEERING

SEP 2015 - MAR 2017

The University of Washington, Seattle; GPA 3.92/4.0

Relevant Courses: User-Centered Design, Usability Studies, Data Science for UX Researchers, Visual Communication, Interaction Design & Prototyping, Machine Learning (Coursera).

BACHELOR'S IN ELECTRONICS & COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING

AUG 2006 - JUN 2010

Visvesvaraya Technological University, Bangalore, India; GPA 6.9/10.0

Awards

BEST GRADUATE CAPSTONE PROJECT - PUMP IT UP

JUN 2017

University of Washington, Seattle

Explored solutions to reduce water waste in Indian homes by designing an Android app + IOT system that provides contextual information & better control over existing water systems to the residents.